Risk management is a major topic for the
PMP exam and this is lesson 12.
Now some of the learning objectives then
for risk management.
First of all, you need to understand
exactly what is a risk.
So we'll be talking about that,
talking about the different types of risk,
so you need to understand the reasons for
doing risk management, right?
You need to comprehend the reason for
performing risk management on a project.
We'll also be talking about some of the
tools.
There's a lot of tools and
techniques that we'll be
covering, right, for identifying
risk and analyzing risks.
We're talking about quantitative risk
analysis and qualitative risk analysis.
So you need to understand all the tools
for that.
Also, you'll need to know how to calculate
EMV, expected monetary value.
So we'll cover that in one of the videos.
Also, we're going to use expected monetary
value to create a decision tree.
So we'll learn how to create decision
tree.
And then once you've identified risk and
you've done all the analysis on the risk,
then how do we respond to the risk?
Right, and there's different
ways of responding to a risk
based on whether it's a
negative risk or a positive risk.
So you need to understand that.
How are we going to respond to negative
and positive risks?